#### Contact

eandersonaz@msn.com

www.linkedin.com/in/eric-anderson-42573989 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Nursing
Healthcare Management
ACLS

Certifications
ACLS, BLS
CCRN-CMC-CSC

# **Eric Anderson**

BSN, RN, CCRN-CMC-CSC

Sacramento, California

## Summary

20+ years ICU nursing experience with focus on cardiac, vascular, and open heart recovery patients.

10+ years management experience as CVICU/PACU charge nurse and House Supervisor.

5+ years management experience as Telemetry/Step-down charge nurse.

1+ years Level 1 trauma center ICU charge nurse and rapid response team member.

Trained in: ECMO, LVAD, IABP, Impella, CRRT, Lumbar and EVD drains.

Team leading by example and empowerment through servant leadership philosophies.

CCRN-CMC-CSC and past ATCN certifications.

## Experience

Mercy General Hospital (Dignity Health)
Cardiac Surgery ICU-Staff Nurse
September 2014 - Present (5 years 10 months)
Sacramento, California Area

Open heart recovery and relief charge nurse

Chandler Regional Medical Center (Dignity Health)
Critical Care Charge Nurse
February 2013 - August 2014 (1 year 7 months)
Chandler, AZ

Arizona Heart Hospital (Tenet Healthcare) House Supervisor/Staff Nurse 1997 - 2014 (17 years)

Columbia Medical Center (Humana) Phoenix RN 1990 - 1997 (7 years) University of Missouri Health Care LPN 1989 - 1990 (1 year) Columbia, Missouri Area

#### Education

Northern Arizona University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2012 - 2014)

South Mountain Community College
Associate of Arts (A.A.), Liberal Arts and Sciences/Liberal
Studies · (2010 - 2011)

Mesa Community College
Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1991 - 1993)

Columbia Public Schools Practical Nursing
LPN, Licensed Practical/Vocational Nurse Training · (1988 - 1989)